AMIR SEDAGHAT

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Mechanical Engineering and experience in computer hardware. I always love coding and often self taught many different languages using free resources. I wanted to really get a full understanding of the software development and combine it with my hardware background. Hence, I completed my Full Stack Web Development Diploma through Lighthouse Labs. I enjoy creating products that are creative, error free and have amazing features for customers.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Ruby, SQL

FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Rails, JQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, SASS, Git, Redux-Toolkit, OAuth/JWT

TEST FRAMEWORKS Mocha & Chai, Jest, Storybook, Cypress

DATABASES PostgreSQL, MongoDB

COMPUTER HARDWARE Install/Configure/Test, Diagnose/troubleshoot hardware issues

PROJECTS

Mar. 2022 to Mar. 2022 DOTCOIN

A fully functional cryptocurrency application that contains current market stats and news, along with cryptocurrencies'

data and price chart.

Teck Stack: React, Redux-Toolkit, RapidAPI

Feb. 2022 to Feb. 2022 Join A Side

A casual community app where users post a debatable topic, and then vote/comment on one side to see the results in a

given time

Teck Stack: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, React, Tailwind

Mar. 2022 to Mar. 2022 Movie Source

A fully responsive movie application that is based on The Movie Database API. It comes with the most popular movies in

home page and a responsive search-bar. User is able to search his/her favorite movie and get all information about it.

Teck Stack: TypeScript, React

Jan. 2022 to Jan. 2022 QuizApp

An app that user can take/create a quiz, share the result link, and make the created quiz public or private.

Tech Stack: Javascript, HTML, EJS, NodeJS, PostgreSQL

Nov. 2021 to Dec. 2021 TinyApp

A full stack web application built with Node and Express that allows users to shorten long URLs.

Tech Stack: Javascript, Express, NodeJS

EDUCATION

Nov. 2021 to Feb. 2022 Lighthouse Labs

Diploma Full Stack Web Development

Sept. 2020 to Dec. 2020 Coursera

 ${\sf Certificate\ Java\ Programming\ And\ Software\ Engineering\ Fundamentals\ Specialization}$

Mar. 2020 to June 2020 Cisco Systems

Certificate CCNA

2001 to 2005 KNTU University

Bachelor Mechanical Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Mar. 2016 to Nov. 2021 Rail Operator

Autoport Ltd · Toronto, ON

- Split and connected more than 50 railcars per day, much more than daily target

- Handled almost 100 Brand-new vehicles and made it ready for clients

- Done everything safe and in timely fashion without any accident/injury

Jan. 2010 to July 2015 Computer Hardware Specialist

Rayan Rasaneh · Tehran, Iran

- Was in charge of installation and configuration of more than 6 to 8 computer systems per day

- Tested and debugged more than 10 computers per day before handing to clients

- Troubleshoot hardware issues for clients